Guide to the Blukis Onat Applied Sciences (BOAS), Inc. Papers 1968-2010
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
- Tolt Water Filtration Plant, Cultural Resource Assessment of a Potential Burial Area in the Vicinity of The Backwash Solids Disposal Study Area for Seattle Public Utilities (Water Department), King County: report., 1993 (Box-folder 23/5, Project 199013.3 (see also 8707, 9705))
- Tolt Water Filtration Plant, Assessment and Documentation of Puncheon Road Remnants along Swan Loop Road for Seattle Public Utilities (Water Department), King County: black and white prints and negatives; correspondence; field notes; photographic log; and report., 1993 (Box-folder 23/6, Project 199013.4 (see also 8707))
- Cedar River Municipal Watershed, Development of Natural and Cultural Resource Inventories, prepared by Dames & Moore and David Evans Associates, Inc., for Seattle Public Utilities (Water Department), King County: proposal., 1990 November (Box-folder 23/7, Project 199014)
- Chester Morse Lake Temporary Pumping Plant No. 2 in Cedar River Municipal Watershed, Cultural Resources Review for Seattle Public Utilities (Water Department), King County: background documents; correspondence; Environmental Impact Statement sections pertaining to cultural resources., undated, 1990, 1991 (Box-folder 23/8, Project 199014)
- Little Boston Archaeological Site on Point Julia, Artifact Curation, Port Gamble S’Klallam Tribe, Jefferson County: correspondence., 2011 (Box-folder 23/9, Project 199102)
- Big Lake Water System Project, Cultural Resource Survey, Skagit County: black and white prints and negatives; correspondence; field notes; photographic log; bound report and report master with original photographs., 1991 (Box-folder 23/10-11, Project 199104)
- Selected King County Parks Properties, Cultural Resource Assessment, and Geoarchaeological Survey of Tolt River-MacDonald Park, King County: maps; bound report and report master with original photographs, 1991 (Box-folder 24/1-2, Project 199106)
- Selected King County Parks Properties, Geoarchaeological Survey of Tolt River-MacDonald Park, King County: bound report, 1991 September (Box-folder 24/3, Project 199106.1)
- Cedar River Municipal Watershed, Cultural Resources Inventories, Seattle Public Utilities (Water Department), King County: correspondence; cultural resource inventory forms; field notes; report, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 24/4-7, Project 199107 (see 199014))
- Swinomish Reservation Housing Unit Parcel "C," Cultural Resource Identification Survey and Supplemental Survey, Skagit County: reports, 1991, 1993 (Box-folder 24/8, Project 199108.1 and 199108.1a)
- Upper Grouse Creek Watershed, Cultural Resource Inventory, Wallowa-Whitman National Forest, Wallowa Country, Oregon: cultural resource inventory forms; field notes; report, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 24/9-10, Project 199110)
- Proposed Residential/Recreational Park at Jorstad Creek, Cultural Resource Assessment, Mason County: correspondence; field notes; maps; and report., 1991-1992 (Box-folder 25/1, Project 199111)
- Port Gamble S'Klallam Indian Reservation, Cultural Resource Assessments, Kitsap County: correspondence., 2011 (Box-folder 25/2, Project 199112)
- Proposed HUD Subdivision on the Port Gamble S'Klallam Indian Reservation, Cultural Resource Assessment, Kitsap County: report., 1991 December (Box-folder 25/3, Project 199112.1)
- Proposed Tribal Subdivision on the Port Gamble S'Klallam Indian Reservation, Cultural Resource Assessment, Kitsap County: report., 1992 December (Box-folder 25/4, Project 199112.2)
- Proposed Sewer Treatment Project on the Port Gamble S'Klallam Indian Reservation, Cultural Resource Assessment, Kitsap County: report., 1993 December (Box-folder 25/5, Project 199112.3)
- Proposed Tolt Pipeline, Phase II, near Redmond, Cultural Resource Assessment, King County: color prints and negatives; field notes; maps; and bound report and report master with original photographs., 1991-1992 (Box-folder 25/6-7, Project 199113)
- Indian Island Collections especially 45JE16, NAGPRA Inventory Review: correspondence and collection lists., 1991-1993 (Box-folder 25/8, Project 199114)
- Proposed Natural Gas Pipeline across a Portion of the Swinomish Indian Reservation, Cultural Resource Assessment and Trench Monitoring, Skagit County: reports., 1992 (Box-folder 25/9, Project 199115.1, 199115.2)
- Proposed New Swinomish Dental Clinic, Cultural Resource Testing, Skagit County: report., 1993 October (Box-folder 25/10, Project 199201.2)
- Bellingham Parks, Cultural Resource Survey, Skagit County: correspondence; field notes; and report (3-page letter)., 1992 (Box-folder 25/11, Project 199203)
- Forest Practice Applications #1914722 and #19194723 Swinomish Reservation, Cultural Resource Assessment, Skagit County: report., 1992 April (Box-folder 25/12, Project 199204)
- Six Bridge Replacement Projects in Snohomish County, Cultural Resources Survey: color prints and negatives; correspondence; field notes; photographic log; and report., 1993-1994 (Box-folder 25/13, Project 199205.1)
- Eight Bridge Replacement Projects and Two Road Widening Projects in Snohomish County, Cultural Resources Survey: bridge HAER forms; color prints and negatives; correspondence; field notes; maps; photographic log; and report., 1994 (Box-folder 25/14, Project 199205.2)
- Historic Bridges and Tunnels in Snohomish County, Inventory: report., 1994 (Box-folder 25/15, Project 199205.3)
- Proposed Twin Rivers Golf Course, Fall City, Cultural Resource Assessment, Follow-up Augur Testing and Monitoring, King County: black and white prints and negatives; reports., 1992-1993 (Box-folder 26/1, Project 199206, 199206.1, 199206.2, 199206.3)
- SR 5 Toutle Park Road to SR 12 West, Archaeological Resources Phase 1 Survey for Washington State Department of Transportation: black and white prints and negatives; correspondence; field notes; and report., 1992-1993 (Box-folder 26/2-3, Project 199207.1)
- SR 5 Toutle Park Road to SR 12 West, Historic Structures Phase 1 Survey: black and white prints and negatives; correspondence; field note and 42LE189 test unit forms; and report., 1993-1995 (Box-folder 26/4-5, Project 199207.2)
- SR 5 Toutle Park Road to SR 12 West and Sites 45LE189, 45LE290, 45TN228, and 45LE125, Phase 2 Archaeological Test Excavations Results and Treatment Recommendations for Sites Completed for Washington State Department of Transportation, Lewis and Thurston Counties: background research photocopies; black and white prints and negatives; correspondence; field notes and forms; maps; stratigraphic profiles; and bound report and report master with original photographs., 1995-1996 (Box-folder 26/6-9, Project 199207.3)
- SR 5 Toutle Park Road to SR 12 West and Sites 45LE189, 45LE290, 45TN228, and 45LE125, Phase 2 Archaeological Test Excavations Results and Treatment Recommendations for Sites Completed for Washington State Department of Transportation: artifacts (10 bags - bone, charcoal, lithics)., 1995-1996 (Box-folder 72/4-13, Project 199207.3)
- SR5 Toutle Park Road to SR 12 West, North County Line Interchange and Larabee Road Interchange, Archaeological Resources and Historic Structures Phase 1 Survey for Washington State Department of Transportation, Lewis County: black and white photos and negatives; field notes; and report., 1999 (Box-folder 26/10, Project 199207.4)
- SR 5 Toutle Park Road to SR 12 West, Archaeological Resources and Historic Structures Survey for Washington State Department of Transportation: highway construction map., undated (Box-folder 76/5, Project 199207)
- 132nd and 140th Streets near Renton, Cultural Resource Assessment, King County: report., 1992 (Box-folder 26/11, Project 199208)
- RESTRICTED -- Cle Elum, Kachess, and Keechelus Lakes, Cultural Resource Survey of the Drawdown Zones, Cle Elum Ranger District, Wenatchee National Forest, Kittitas County: bound reports., 1993 (Box-folder 58R/2-4, Project 199209 (199209.1, 199209.2, 199209.3))
- RESTRICTED -- Cle Elum, Kachess, and Keechelus Lakes, Cultural Resource Survey of the Drawdown Zones, Cle Elum Ranger District, Wenatchee National Forest, Kittitas County: photocopies of USGS topographic maps marked with cultural resource locations marked., [1992-1993 ] (Box-folder 77R/1, Project 199209)
- RESTRICTED -- Twin Buttes Planning Area, Mt. Adams Ranger District, and Velvet Planning Area, Randle Ranger District, Cultural Resources Survey and Testing, Gifford Pinchot National Forest, Lewis and Skamania Counties: artifact catalog sheets, field notes, photographic log, copies of topographic maps with project areas marked, and reports., 1993 (Box-folder 58R/5-6, Project 199210.1 199210.2)
- Gifford Pinchot National Forest, Assessment of Subsurface Testing as a Component of Cultural Resource Surveys to Aid In Site Discovery in Western Cascade Environments: report., 1994 (Box-folder 27/1, Project 199210.3)
- Stevens Pass Historic District, Archaeological Materials Analysis from Iron Goat Testing Project, Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest, King County: report., 1993 (Box-folder 27/2, Project 199211)
- RESTRICTED -- Palouse Canyon Archeological District, Site Testing for Walla Walla District of US Army Corps of Engineers (COE), Franklin and Whitman County: correspondence regarding proposal and contract; previously recorded sites forms (1948, 1960, 1966, 1975, 1978, 1979, 1983, 1987-1989, including Palouse Canyon Archaeological District National Register of Historic Places Nomination Form (1983)); technical proposal, original and amended; and original contract between COE and BOAS (1992) and contract modifications (1992-1994)., 1948, 1960, 1966, 1975, 1978, 1979, 1983, 1987-1989, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 59R/1-6, Project 199212)
- RESTRICTED -- Palouse Canyon Archeological District, Site Testing for Walla Walla District of US Army Corps of Engineers (COE), 1992 Field Season, Franklin County: correspondence including monthly progress reports and radiocarbon dating results; report (2 volumes)., 1992-1993 (Box-folder 59R/7-9, Project 199212.1)
- RESTRICTED -- Palouse Canyon Archeological District, Site Testing for Walla Walla District of US Army Corps of Engineers (COE), 1993 Field Season including Testing of McGregor Cave (45FR201), Franklin County: correspondence with monthly progress and consultant reports; McGregor Cave (45FR201) stratigraphic profiles, geological sample logs, drafts of report appendices C and D; bound report, 2 volumes., 1993-1994 (Box-folder 60R/1-4, Project 199212.2)
- RESTRICTED -- Palouse Canyon Archeological District, Site Testing for Walla Walla District of US Army Corps of Engineers (COE), 1994 Field Season including Testing of Porcupine Cave (45FR202), Franklin County: color prints; correspondence with monthly progress and consultant reports; Porcupine Cave (45FR202) field-generated bag catalog sheets, lab-generated bag catalog sheets, lab processing notes, textile analysis, lithic analysis, geoarchaeological samples catalog, carbon samples catalog; and bound report, 2 volumes., 1994-1995 (Box-folder 60R/5-9, Project 199212.3)
- RESTRICTED -- Palouse Canyon Archeological District, Site Testing for Walla Walla District of US Army Corps of Engineers (COE), 1994 Field Season including Testing of Porcupine Cave (45FR202), Franklin County: color prints; correspondence with monthly progress and consultant reports; Porcupine Cave (45FR202) collection bag catalog sheets, lab processing notes, textile analysis, lithic analysis, geoarchaeological samples catalog, carbon samples catalog; and bound report, 2 volumes., 1994-1995 (Box-folder 61R/1-3, Project 199212.3)
- RESTRICTED -- Palouse Canyon Archeological District, Culture Resources Management Recommendations and Site Testing for Walla Walla District of US Army Corps of Engineers (COE), 1995 Field Season including Testing of 45FR404 (T42), 45FR428 (T8), 45FR444 (T34), 45WT206 (T32), Franklin and Whitman County: color prints and photographic log from field season; correspondence with monthly progress and consultant report; faunal analysis report with 3.5 inch floppy disk; magnetic survey with plots; and bound report, 1 volume field results and other management document., 1995-1996 (Box-folder 61R/4-9, Project 199212.4)
- RESTRICTED -- Palouse Canyon Archeological District, Walla Walla District of US Army Corps of Engineers (COE): multiple large format (29"x44" and larger) maps of Palouse Canyon Archeological District and photocopy of topographic map. No site locations., 1993 (Box-folder 77R/2, Project 199212)
- RESTRICTED -- Palouse Canyon Archeological District, Walla Walla District of US Army Corps of Engineers (COE): Poster board map (20"x32") with district boundaries and individual site locations, labeled Figure 1.1 from 1995 Field Season Report., 1996 (Box-folder 78R/, Project 199212.4)
- Sheep Burnside Sites (35LIN391 and 35LIN392), Sevenmile Creek (South Santiam River) Drainage, Archaeological Data Recovery Investigations, Willamette National Forest, Linn County, Oregon: correspondence; US Forest Service site reports; field and lab notes; specialized analysis reports such as hydration analysis; and bound report and report master with original photographs., 1993-1995 (Box-folder 27/3-5, Project 199213)
- Morse Pump Plant, Rattlesnake Lake and Boxley Creek, Cultural Resources Mitigation, for Seattle Public Utilities (Water Department), King County: draft and final report., 1993-1994 (Box-folder 27/6-7, Project 199214)
- RESTRICTED -- 45LE263, Camp Creek Rockshelter, Formed Tool Analysis of Lithic and Bone Tools Recovered from Test Excavations in 1985, Gifford Pinchot National Forest, Lewis County: laboratory notes and report., 1993 (Box-folder 62R/1, Project 199215)
- RESTRICTED -- Sites 45SK222 (petroglyph) and 45SK223 (lithic scatter) and Tewalt (Beaver Lake) Quarry Project, Cultural Resource Survey for Citizens Committee to Preserve Nookachamps Valley, Skagit County: black and white petroglyph photographs; 5.25 inch floppy disk; correspondence; court documents; expert witness reports; maps with site locations; newspaper articles; site forms; and "expert witness" reports analyzing petroglyph authenticity., 1992-1995 (Box-folder 62R/2-3, Project 199216)
- Swinomish Reservation, Carlson Property, Forest Practices Application #FP1915768, Cultural Resources Assessment, Skagit County: report., 1992 December (Box-folder 28/1, Project 199217)
- Swinomish Reservation, Elsie Andres Allotment, Coastal Zone Development Permit #CZM9209005, Forest Practices Application #FP1915625, Cultural Resources Assessment, Skagit County: report., 1992 December (Box-folder 28/2, Project 199218)
- Well Spring (Upper and Lower) Oregon Trail Site, Listed on National Register of Historic Places, Archaeological and Historical Research and Resources Survey for National Park Service, Naval Weapons System Testing Facility, Boardman, Morrow County, Oregon: black and white contact sheets, prints, and negatives; correspondence; field notes; paper and diazo plots of surface cultural artifacts; photographic log; camera-ready report and bound copy., 1994-1995 (Box-folder 28/3-4, Project 199300.1)
- Mount Rainier National Park, Review and Assessment of the Ethnographic Literature of Mount Rainier National Park with Annotated Bibliography, for National Park Service: 2 data CDs; annotated bibliography; correspondence; research notes; "Tahoma Legends - History in Two Voices," Journal of Northwest Anthropology 40:1 (Spring 2006); original figures for "Tahoma Legends"; report., 1993-1999 (Box-folder 28/5, Project 199300.2)
- Pickering Barn, Listed on National Register of Historic Places, Historic and Cultural Resources for Pickering Corporate Park Environmental Impact Statement, Issaquah, King County: report., n.d. (Box-folder 29/1, Project 199301)
- Proposed Tolt Pipeline No. 2, Phase III, across the Snoqualmie River Valley, Cultural Resource Assessment, King County: report., 1993 March (Box-folder 29/2, Project 199302)
- Tacoma Narrows Bridge/SR 16, Cultural Resource Investigation of 6-mile Segment for Washington State Department of Transportation, District 4, Pierce County: black and white prints and negatives; field notes; and report., 1994 (Box-folder 29/3, Project 199303)
- Swinomish Reservation, Forest Practices Application FP1915922, Cultural Resources Assessment, Skagit County: report., 1993 March (Box-folder 29/4, Project 199304)
- Swinomish Reservation, Forest Practices Application FP1916332, Cultural Resources Assessment, Skagit County: report., 1993 September (Box-folder 29/5, Project 199305)
- Catherine Creek and Major Creek Drainages in Southwestern Klickitat County, Columbia River Gorge National Scenic Area, Cultural Resources Inventory and Evaluation, for US Forest Service: correspondence and report., 1994-1995 (Box-folder 29/6-7, Project 199306)
- Catherine Creek and Major Creek Drainages in Southwestern Klickitat County, Columbia River Gorge National Scenic Area, Cultural Resources Inventory and Evaluation, for US Forest Service: 3 Metzger Map company diazo property maps and photocopies of them, 1 photocopy GLO 1883 map T3N R11E., 1883, 1934 (Box-folder 76/6, Project 199306)
- U.S. Coast Guard Air Station Sitka, Sitka, Alaska, Archaeological and Historical Survey and Inventory: black and white aerial photos and paper copies; color prints and negatives; correspondence; field notes; interview notes; original figures for report; and camera-ready report and bound copy., 1994-1995 (Box-folder 29/8-11, Project 199307.1)
- U.S. Coast Guard Support Center Kodiak, Kodiak, Alaska, Archaeological Survey by subcontractor Northern Land Use Research for BOAS Inc., who is subcontracted by Richard Carothers Associates for US Coast Guard, Maintenance and Logistics Command, Alameda, CA: 2 3.5 inchand 1 5 1/4 inch floppy disks; correspondence; contract and supporting documents; and report., 1995-1996 (Box-folder 30/1-2, Project 199307.2)
- Surface Water Management Division in Department of Public Works, Archaeological and Cultural Resources Project Reviews, King County: correspondence; field notes; and 59 letter reports on various projects., 1994-1996 (Box-folder 30/3, Project 199308)
- Northwest Regional Power Facility (NRPF), Proposed Creston Site, Historic and Cultural Resources Review for Energy Facility Site Evaluation Council (EFSEC): section of report on historic and cultural resources., 1994 (Box-folder 30/4, Project 199401)
- Westshore Wastewater Project, Archaeological Survey and Testing, Swinomish Indian Tribal Community, Skagit County: report with addendum., 1994 March (Box-folder 30/5, Project 199402)
- Hanford Cultural Resources Project, Pacific Northwest Laboratories, Richland Operations Office of Department of Energy, External Peer Review Panel EPRP), Sheila Stump of BOAS one of members: agenda and presentations to EPRP; EPRP report., 1994 (Box-folder 30/6, Project 199403)
- Mountain Loop Highway Construction, Cultural Resource Inventory and Research, Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest, Snohomish County: camera-ready report and bound copy., 1996 (Box-folder 30/7-8, Project 199404)
- Mountain Loop Highway Construction, Cultural Resource Inventory and Research, Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest, Snohomish County: highway project maps., 1994 (Box-folder 76/7, Project 199404)
- Two Road Improvement Projects, 100th Street SE (SR 527 to 35th Ave SE) and 112th Street (I-5 to SR 99), Cultural Resources Assessment for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: correspondence; maps; original and bound report., 1995 (Box-folder 30/9, Project 199405.1 (see also 200004.16))
- Airport Road HOV (High Occupancy Vehicle) - SR 99 to SR 526, Cultural Resources Assessment for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: field notes; inventory forms; project maps; and 2-page letter report., 1995 (Box-folder 31/1, Project 199405.2 (see also 200004.16))
- Woods Creek (#6) and Lake Stevens (#125) Bridges, Cultural Resources Investigation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: correspondence; field notes; project maps; 3-page letter report., 1995-1996 (Box-folder 31/2, Project 199405.3 (see also 200004.15))
- 132nd Steet SE Project, Cultural Resources Investigation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: color prints; field notes; project map; and report., 1996-1997 (Box-folder 31/3, Project 199405.4)
- Green River Trail, Phase II Cultural Resource Survey for MacLeod Reckord, Landscape Architects, King County: project maps and report., 1995 (Box-folder 31/4, Project 199501.1)
- North Wind Weir Park Restroom, Cultural Resource Investigations for MacLeod Reckord, Landscape Architects, King County: correspondence; field notes; 5-page letter report., 1996-1997 (Box-folder 31/5, Project 199501.2)
- North Wind Weir as part of Green River Trail, Phase II Cultural Resource Survey for MacLeod Reckord, Landscape Architects, King County: correspondence regarding trail's impact on weir, tribal consultations, and interpretive signage., 1995-1998 (Box-folder 31/6, Project 199501.3)
- North Wind Weir Park, Archaeological Monitoring of Geological Coring for Intertidal Area for MacLeod Reckord, Landscape Architects, King County: correspondence and report of results from hand auger borings and geotechnical drilling., 1997 (Box-folder 31/7, Project 199501.4)
- Proposed Fiber Optic Route Through Deception Pass State Park, Archaeological Survey, Island County: black and white aerial photos and negatives; correspondence; field notes; and report., 1995 (Box-folder 31/8, Project 199503)
- Four Sites (45SK2, 45SK3, 45SK213, 45SK214) in the Cypress Island Natural Resource Conservation Area, Archaeological Protection of Sites, Washington State Department of Natural Resources (DNR), Skagit County: color prints and negatives; correspondence and proposal; project maps; DNR management plan and request for proposal; report figures; site inventory forms; and reports for each site: 45SK2=199504.1; 45SK3=199504.2; 45SK213=199504.3; 45SK214=199504.4., 1994-1995 (Box-folder 31/9-13, Project 199504, 199504.1-199504.4)
- 45SK224, Similk Bay, Testing of Site, Skagit County: correspondence; black and white and color prints and negatives; field notes; maps; 5-page letter report., 1994-1995, 2000 (Box-folder 31/14, Project 199505)
- 45IS13 (Snakelum Point), Nemnick Property, Archaeological Investigations, Island County: 6-page letter report., 1995 September 15 (Box-folder 31/15, Project 199506.1)
- New Swinomish Dental Building Site, Archaeological Investigation, Skagit County: 5-page letter report., 1995 September 18 (Box-folder 31/16, Project 199507)
- 45SA222, Trout Creek Site,Wind River Ranger Station, Historic Artifact Analysis by Western Resources Consulting (WRC) for BOAS, Gifford Pinchot National Forest (GPNF), Skamania County: GPNF-provided scope of work; artifact catalog; WRC progress report., 1996 (Box-folder 31/17, Project 199508.2)
- Proposed SR-20/South March Point Road Interchange Improvements Project, Cultural Resource Assessment, Skagit County: report., 1995 October (Box-folder 32/1, Project 199509)
- Proposed Aldarra Farm Golf Course, Archaeological Resource Assessment, King County: original report and bound copy., 1995 (Box-folder 32/2, Project 199510)
- Proposed Rocky Reach Trailway, Archaeological investigations for Washington State Parks, Douglas County: correspondence; field notes; maps; study proposal; and report., 1996 (Box-folder 32/3, Project 199511)
- Bear Paw Resorts Inc., La Push Project, Cultural Resouce Assessment for Williams Architects, Clallam County: black and white prints and negatives; architect site report; correspondence; field notes; maps; 7-page letter report., 1995-1996 (Box-folder 32/4, Project 199601)
- Swinomish Channel Marina South of Highway 20, Cultural Resource Survey, Skagit County: unbound report., 1996 (Box-folder 32/5, Project 199602.5s)